<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure on Marks Multiverse</title><link>https://marksmultiverse.com/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in Azure on Marks Multiverse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 10:00:46 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marksmultiverse.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automate Azure Image Builder in Bicep with custom builder resource group</title><link>https://marksmultiverse.com/docs/bicep-automate-aib/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 10:00:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marksmultiverse.com/docs/bicep-automate-aib/</guid><description>Of course we want to secure and keep our Azure tenant tidy with the help of Azure Policies. And without any hesitation I preach to automate everything! But what if these two mindsets conflict with one another? What if there is an Azure Policy in place that demands a naming standard or tags for resource groups that causes an automated Azure Image Builder deployment to fail? \
With Azure Image Builder (AIB) we can automate the process of building images for use in an Azure Virtual Desktop environment for instance.</description></item><item><title>Automate creation of test databases on Azure SQL with Active Directory security groups</title><link>https://marksmultiverse.com/docs/azure-automate-testdb-azuresql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 14:00:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marksmultiverse.com/docs/azure-automate-testdb-azuresql/</guid><description>For database testing it is customary to make periodic copies of the production database and use the latest copy as a test database. But how does that work in a scenario where you use Azure SQL and a traditional Active Directory instance? And on top of that you obviously want to automate that process!
Steps Steps involved:
Create an Automation Account. Give the automation account the right permissions. Make the automation account administrator on the SQL server.</description></item></channel></rss>